https://www.alexandrahospital.on.ca/privacy

Privacy PolicyHomePrivacy PolicyShare this Page
HomeEmergency DepartmentAreas of CareDiabetes Education CentreDiagnostic ImagingGeneral X-RayUltrasoundsPelvic UltrasoundsEchocardiogramObstetrical or Pregnancy UltrasoundMedical / Surgical UnitPatient & Family InformationLocation & DirectionsGive Back & DonateOur CampaignContact the FoundationWays to GiveGifts at WorkDonor RecognitionAbout UsPhoto GalleryFoundation EventsVendor ProgramGet in TouchAbout AHIWelcome to AHIMission, Vision, ValuesStandards of Performance for Team MembersJoint Strategic PlanAHI BoardBoard RecruitmentOur Leadership TeamAccessibility GuidelinesQuality & Patient SafetyReporting - C-DifficileReporting - MRSA BacteraemiaReporting - VRE BacteraemiaReporting - Hand HygieneAccountabilityAccreditationPrivacy EducationPrivacy Education - Module 1Privacy Education - Module 2Privacy Education - Module 3Privacy Education - Module 4Privacy Education - Module 5Scenario - ProfessionalsScenario - Regulated Health ProfessionalsScenario - Clinical Support Team MembersScenario - Non-Clinical Support Team MembersOur Education CentreCOVID-19CareersWelcome to AHIAbout Ingersoll & AreaKey ContactsLatest OpportunitiesProfessional Staff OrientationHospital Policies & ProceduresVolunteerAHI Volunteer ServicesTypes of Volunteer RolesApply to be a VolunteerLatest NewsAccessibilityCommunity ResourcesCampus of CareSend a Patient E-Card
Click here to Donate
Your Privacy is important to us!Alexandra Hospital is committed to keep your personal health information safe and confidential.  Your privacy is very important to us.  We are continuously monitoring policies and procedures to further protect the privacy of your information.What type of information do we collect about you?To provide you with quality health care, we collect both personal and health information from you.  Your legal name, date of birth, address, Health Card Number and extended health insurance numbers are examples of personal information.  Your health history, the records of your visits to the hospital and what health care we provide to you during those visits are examples of your health information.Personal Health Information Protection Act (PHIPA)PHIPA is provincial legislation that protects personal information, including health information.  It sets out ten principles that organizations, individuals, associations, partnerships and trade unions must follow when collecting, using and disclosing personal information in the course of a commercial activity.PHIPA is formulated on the basis of the Canadian National Standard code commonly known as the ten fair information principles.Alexandra Hospital is implementing a privacy program based on these principles, which are listed below.The 10 Privacy Principles of PHIPAAccountabilityAccuracyIdentifying PurposesSafeguardsConsentOpennessLimiting CollectionIndividual AccessLimiting Use, Disclosure and RetentionChallenging ComplianceAccountability
An organization is responsible for personal information under its control and shall designate an individual or individuals who are accountable for the organization's compliance with the following principles.Identifying Purposes
The purposes for which personal information is collected shall be identified by the organization at or before the time the information is collected.Consent
The knowledge and consent of an individual are required for the collection, use, or disclosure of personal information, except where appropriate.Limiting Collection
The collection of personal information shall be limited to that which is necessary for the purposes identified by the organization.  Information shall be collect by fair and lawful means.Limiting Use, Disclosure and Retention
Personal information shall not be used or disclosed for purposes other than those for which it was collected, except with the consent of the individual or as required by law.  Persona information shall be retained only as long as necessary for the fulfillment of those purposes.Accuracy
Personal information shall be as accurate, complete and up-to-date as is necessary for the purpose for which it is used.Safeguards
Personal information shall be protected by security safeguards appropriate to the sensitivity of the information.Openness
An organization shall make readily available to individuals specific information about its policies and practices relating to the management of personal informationIndividual Access
Upon request, an individual shall be informed of the existence, use, and disclose of his or her personal information, and shall be given access to that information.  An individual shall be able to challenge the accuracy and completeness of the information and have it amended as appropriate.Challenging Compliance
An individual shall be able to address a challenge concerning compliance with the above principles to the designate individuals accountable for the organization's compliance.How is your information used?The information we collect from you is used:To provide you with quality health care and follow up care in the community;To carry out quality assurance to make us better;For patient satisfaction surveys to see how we are doing; andTo comply with legal and regulatory requirements.For research to make the Alexandra Hospital the best we can be and to help develop new treatments and technologies for the future; andFor education to keep current health care practitioners up to date and to train new health care practitioners for the future.If your information is to be used for any other purpose, your specific permission would be required first.Do we share your information with anyone?Alexandra Hospital does share your personal and health information with health care providers at other hospitals, health care agencies, nursing homes, etc. who become part of your health care team for the purpose of your continuing care.  Your information is shared with agencies authorized by law, for example, OHIP, health insurance companies and the Workplace Safety and Insurance Board.
TILLSONBURG DISTRICTMEMORIAL HOSPITALALEXANDRA HOSPITALINGERSOLLVISIT TILLSONBURG HOSPITAL WEBSITEGET MAP & DIRECTIONSTDMH FOUNDATIONAREAS OF CARECAREERSSEND A PATIENT E-CARDVISIT ALEXANDRA HOSPITAL WEBSITEGET MAP & DIRECTIONSAH FOUNDATIONAREAS OF CARECAREERSSEND A PATIENT E-CARDTILLSONBURG DISTRICTMEMORIAL HOSPITALVISIT TILLSONBURG HOSPITAL WEBSITEGET MAP & DIRECTIONSTDMH FOUNDATIONAREAS OF CARECAREERSSEND A PATIENT E-CARDALEXANDRA HOSPITALINGERSOLLVISIT ALEXANDRA HOSPITAL WEBSITEGET MAP & DIRECTIONSAHI FOUNDATIONAREAS OF CARECAREERSSEND A PATIENT E-CARD
